A Guide to the Paul Ehrlich and Martha Marquardt papers (Wellcome collection) FA136
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Martha Marquardt Material, 2
  - Karl Weigert material, 1845-1904 1956 1957 1959 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Karl Weigert, a distant relative of Carl Weigert compiled a family tree with the help of other relatives. This folder contains some photocopies of articles about Karl Weigert, correspondence with The Wellcome Foundation), a typewritten family tree, as well as a schematic drawing of the Weigert family tree.
  - Proofs of Collected Papers (Box 18, Box 19)
    Printer's proofs of "The Collected Papers of Paul Ehrlich".
  - Paul Ehrlich Centennial Celebration, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Articles written on the occasion of various centennial celebrations by: A. Beyer, A. T. Birmingham, Georg Blumenthal, Karl Hermann, Iago Galdston (2), 1 pamphlet describing the celebration of the New York Academy of Medicine, Hermann Pinkus (2), A. Stuhmer, Fritz Trautmann, T. S. Work, 4 other articles by unknown authors (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 3 pamphlets: Indo-German Society, India, The New York Academy of Medicine, Announcement of the publication of "The Collected Papers of Paul Ehrlich" (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Various newspaper clippings of articles commemorating the 100th birthday of Paul Ehrlich, and the Paul Ehrlich Prize in including one by Sir Alexander Fleming, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Invitation to Martha Marquardt from the Wellcome Foundation for the centennial celebration on in London, 1954 March 25 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - 3 articles by Martha Marquardt (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - "Paul Ehrlich - Some Reminiscences", British Medical Journal, 1954 March 20
      - "Ernstes und Heiteres aus Paul Ehrlich's Leben", Aufbau, 1954 March 26
      - "Meine Erinnerungen an Paul Ehrlich", Aufbau, 1954 April 30
    - Notes by Martha Marquardt about articles written by W. R. Bett and George Urdang (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Article by Martha Marquardt entitled "Paul Ehrlich, his 100 Anniversary of Birth-14th March 1954", 30 typewritten pages (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Article by Martha Marquardt entitled "Paul Ehrlich, Zum Hundersten Geburtstag, 14. März 1954", 179 typewritten pages (1 copy each in Folders 4 and 5) (Box 20, Folder 5, Folder 4)
    - Invitation to Martha Marquardt for the Ehrlich-Behring celebration in Frankfurt, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 9 photographs of Martha Marquardt at celebration (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 1 commemorative envelope (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 1 booklet "Behringwerk Mitteilungen", 1954 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 1 booklet published by Hoechst about the Ehrlich-Behring Centennial (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 1 photograph album presented to Martha Marquardt of pictures taken during the centennial celebration (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Martha Marquardt film material, Some of Martha Marquardt's photographic material could not be shipped to New York as was, because of flammability of the old nitrate films and negatives; copies were made (Box 21)
    - untitled, 2 rolls of film
      Conditions Governing Access
      RAC is unable to provide access to the original item, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
    - untitled, 4 empty boxes (presumably the original rolls were in these)
    - untitled, 21 small plastic bags containing tissue papers and labels, but no negatives
    - Photographed anatomical sections, 34 small prints
    - untitled, 2 photographic filters
  - Sir Almroth Wright material
    - Reprints, 7 reprints (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - On the general principles of the therapeutic inoculation of bacterial vaccines as applied to the treatment of tuberculous infection, 1905
      - The inoculation treatment of tuberculosis, 1906
      - On the foundation of Serum therapy, 1906
      - On some points in connection with vaccine-therapy and therapeutic immunization generally, 1908
      - Vaccine therapy: its administration, value, and limitations, 1910
      - Suffrage Fallacies, (a letter reprinted from The London Times)., 1912
      - Brief Survey of the History and Development of the inoculation department, St. Mary's Hospital, no date, 7 reprints
    - Pamphlet entitled: The presentation of a bust to Sir Almroth Wright on the occasion of Wright's 75th birthday, 2 items (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Article about Wright in The London Times, 1946 August 10 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Obituary material: Memorial Service, pamphlet, 1861-1947 May 8, 19?? (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Paper clippings from The Times, The Listener and Sunday Chronicle (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Reprint from the Obituary Notices of Fellows of The Royal Society, 19?? (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 1 photograph of Wright (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Related Materials
      The extensive correspondence between Martha Marquardt and Wright is in Box 12, Folder 9.
  - Books
    - Colebrook, Leonard, Almroth Wright, 1954 (Box 23)
    - Colebrook, Leonard, A new approach to the treatment of burns and scalds, 1950 (Box 23)
    - Marquardt, Martha, Paul Ehrlich als Mensch und Arbeiter, 1924; 2 items (Box 23)
    - Marquardt, Martha, Paul Ehrlich, 1949 (Box 23)
    - Shiga, Kiyoshi, Paul Ehrlich biography in Japanese, 1948 (Box 23)
    - Venzmer, Gerhard, Paul Ehrlich, Leben und Wirken, 1948 (Box 23)
    - Hessen, Kultur und Wirtschaft, 1952 (Box 23)
  - Journals, Pamphlets, Reprints, Paper clippings
    - Journals: (not in folder) (Box 24)
      - Life and Letters, 1945 1946; 3 items
      - Lumière et Jougla.
      - Reader's Digest, 1946
    - Pamphlets (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Gedenkrede auf Ludwig Aschoff, von Franz Buchner
      - Friedliche Eroberer - Albert Einstein und Paul Ehrlich
      - Luther und die Musik
      - Mallorca
      - Radioaktive Leuchtfarben
      - Neue Aussichten
      - Münzensystem aller Lander
      - Article by Winston Churchill - Clemenceau — the Man and the Tiger
    - Reprints
      - Himmelweit, Fred, 1933 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Holt, Lewis, 1947 1950 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Noguchi, H., 1913 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Richter, Rud. u. E. (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Schuckmann, W. r., 1926; 2 items (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Arbeiten aus dem Staatsinstitut für Experimentelle Therapie, 1924 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Botanische Ausflüge in der Umgegend von Frankfurt am Main, 1920 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Geologische Exkursionen in der Umgegend von Frankfurt am Main, 1920; 3 items (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Box 24, Folder 3)